The young Britannian Lelouch has two paths.
ブリタニアの少年 ルルーシュは
２つの道を持っている
One is a path leading to the past as
he searches for his mother's enemies.
１つは母の仇を探す過去への道
The other, a path to the future as he creates a place...
もう１つは 妹 ナナリーが
幸せに過ごせる場所を作る為の
where his younger sister
Nunnally can be happy.
未来への道
As Lelouch gazes at the past and the future,
ルルーシュが過去と未来を見据えた時
will the current path to follow
that he alone can choose...
彼だけが選べる現在の道は
be to destroy the world,
or to build a new one?
世界の破壊か 世界の構築か
Yumemiteta yume
The dream that I dreamed
夢見てた夢
果て無き遠く
Hatenai tooku
Endless and distant
乾いた日々の 空色・手の中
Kawaita hibi no sorairo, te no naka
The sky-blue of dry days, in my hands
等間隔 音の中で試行錯誤
Toukankaku oto no naka de
In the space between each tick of the clock
Shikousakugo
Trial and error
時間・間隔の無い空間
Jikan kankaku no nai kuukan
A space without distance or time
等身大 音をたてて
Toushindai oto wo tatete
Making a life-sized sound
僕の顔　造って行く
Boku no kao tsukutte yuku
It defines my face
キレイに　片方だけ
Kirei ni katahou dake
Cleanly, but only one side
この手に落ちた
Kono te ni ochita
This rotting apple...
腐りかけのリンゴ
Kusarikake no ringo
That's fallen into my hand
鏡に映る　僕らの裏側まで
Kagami ni utsuru
Reflecting in the mirror
Bokura no uragawa made
Even showing our other side
Toukankaku oto no naka de
In the space between each tick of the clock
遠感覚 人の中で試行錯誤
Shikousakugo
Trial and error
時間・感覚の無い空間
Jikan kankaku no nai kuukan
A space without distance or time
Toushindai tsume wo tatete
With life-sized claws bared
頭身台 爪をたてて
Boku no kao wo kezutte yuku
I shave my face
僕の顔　削って行く
Kirei ni katahou dake
Cleanly, but only one side
キレイに　片方だけ
Toukankaku
A distant sensation
－遠感覚
Toukankaku
A distant sensation
I ORDER YOU, SUZAKU KURURUGI
バイク１台調達するのにも
苦労してたってのに 潜水艦か
We used to have trouble getting even one
motorcycle, and now we have a submarine...
I know the Indian military district
doesn't want her discovered here,
インド軍区だって
ばれたらヤバいはずなのに
but just how did that woman arrange all this?
どういうルート使ったんだろう？
あの女
それでは黒の騎士団再編成による
新組織図を発表する
Now then, I'll announce our new organizational
plan since the reorganization of the Black Knights.
軍事の総責任者に藤堂鏡志朗
The chief of military affairs
will now be Kyoshiro Tohdoh.
おお…
うん
情報全般 広報 諜報 渉外の総責任者に
ディートハルト・リート
In charge of general intelligence, including public
relations, spying, and liaison work... Diethard Reid.
このブリタニア人が？
This Britannian?!
しかもメディアの人間だぞ
Not just that, he's with the media!
ゼロ
Zero, I don't mean to be racist,
but what's the reason...
民族に こだわるつもりはないが
わざわざブリタニア人を
起用する理由は？
for using a Britannian in
such an important position?
理由？
Reason? Well then, what about me?
では私はどうなる？
う…
As you all know, I'm not Japanese, either.
知っての通り 私も日本人ではない
必要なのは結果を出せる能力だ
What we need here are
talents which get results!
人種も 過去も手段も関係ない
Race, past, and methods don't matter!
All right! All right!
分かった 分かったよ
副指令は扇要
My second in command is Kaname Ohgi.
俺が？
Me?
不服か？
You object?
い… いや…
N- No...
ま 元々のリーダーは扇だし
Well, Ohgi was our leader to begin with.
新参者じゃあ ちょっとな
I was getting worried with all these newcomers.
技術開発担当にラクシャータ
In charge of engineering
and development: Rakshata.
当然
Naturally.
零番隊 隊長　紅月カレン
Commander of Zero Squad: Kallen Kouzuki.
零番隊？
"Zero Squad?"
零番隊だけは 私の直轄となる
Zero Squad alone will be under my direct control.
親衛隊と考えてもらえればいい
You can think of it as a sort of royal guard.
親衛隊… ゼロの
A royal guard... Zero's!
一番隊隊長 朝比奈省悟
Commander of squad 1 will be Shogo Asahina.
二番隊隊長 仙波崚河
Commander of squad 2: Ryouga Senba.
Commander of squad 3: Kizuna Kagesaki.
三番隊隊長 影崎絆
第二特務隊隊長 玉城真一郎
Commander of special forces squad
2: Shin'ichirou Tamaki. That is all.
以上だ
YES!
よっしゃ！
え？
C.C.は役職なし？
No position for C.C.?
ゼロ １つよろしいでしょうか？
Zero, may I add one thing?
ん？
のちほど協議すべき議題があります
There's a topic we've put off
which needs to be addressed.
I don't care if he's an honorary Britannian.
Making an Eleven a knight is!
名誉ブリタニア人とはいえ
イレヴンが騎士になるとは
And authorizing it live on television!
テレビ放送も許可したとか
How'd he ever win her favor?
どうやって取り入ったのやら
そこはほれ
ユーフェミア様も年頃だから
Just look at her. Princess
Euphemia's an adolescent, after all.
ふふふふふ
Are they serious?!
マジかよ！
This can't be happening!
あり得ねぇだろ こんなの
しかも少佐だって イレヴンが
Not just that, but they made an Eleven a major!
枢木スザク
Suzaku Kururugi.
汝 ここに騎士の誓約をたて
ブリタニアの騎士として戦う事を願うか
Wilt thou swear this day to do
battle as a knight of Britannia?
Yes, Your Highness.
イエス ユア・ハイネス
汝 我欲を捨て 大いなる正義の為に
剣となり盾となる事を望むか？
Wilt thou abandon selfishness and wish to be
sword and shield for the sake of great justice?
イエス ユア・ハイネス
Yes, Your Highness.
わたくし
ユーフェミア・リ・ブリタニアは
I, Euphemia li Britannia, do
dub thee Sir Suzaku Kururugi.
汝 枢木スザクを騎士として認めます
勇気…
This is going to make his being
attached to us complicated.
所属がややこしくなるな
ロイドさんが話は通したみたいですよ
Lloyd seems to have spoken with them about that.
あの方に？
With her?
ええ
私も お会いした事はないのですが
Yes, well, it's not like I've ever met her.
あ… ああ…
枢木スザク
Suzaku Kururugi.
彼はイレヴンの恭順派にとって
旗印になりかねません
He can't be allowed to become a symbol
to Elevens who support Britannia.
私は暗殺を進言します
My advice is that he be assassinated.
暗殺？　枢木をか？
Assassinated? Kururugi?
なるほどね
I see.
反対派にはゼロってスターがいるけど
恭順派にはいなかったからねえ
While Zero has been the star of the resistance
movement, the supporters have lacked one.
人は主義主張だけでは動きません
People don't move on pure ideology.
Now that a person the Britannians
can use as a symbol has appeared,
ブリタニア側に
象徴足りうる人物が現れた今
最も現実的な手段として
暗殺という手があります
the most realistic option
would be to have him killed...
I object.
反対だ
そのような卑怯なやり方では
日本人の支持は得られない
The Japanese people would never
support such a cowardly tactic.
そうです！
That's right! The Black Knights
won't kill an unarmed opponent!
俺達 黒の騎士団は
武器を持たない者は殺さない！
暗殺って 彼が武器を持っていない
プライベートを狙うって事でしょ！
When you say assassinate, you mean kill him
in private, when he's defenseless, don't you?!
私は もっとも確実で
リスクの低い方法を申し上げたまで
I'm just suggesting a way to minimize a definite risk.
決断するのはゼロです
The one who will decide what to do is Zero.
簡単な事だろう？
It's simple, isn't it? Just use
your Geass on Suzaku Kururugi.
枢木スザクにギアスを使えばいい
駄目だ
Forget it.
なぜだ？　意地か それとも友情？
Why not? Stubbornness? Or for friendship?
Out of pride, perhaps?
プライドか？
う！
全部だ
All of it.
たとえ殺す事になっても… か？
Even if you might have to kill him?
く…
何も言っては下さらないのですね
You haven't said anything about it yet.
騎士の任命は皇族の特権だ
総督といえど口を出す資格はない
Appointing a knight is a privilege of royalty.
Even a viceroy has no right to comment on it.
枢木スザクは
名誉ブリタニア人ではありますが
Suzaku Kururugi is an honorary Britannian,
and his talents make him worthy of
being a knight. Sister, even you must...
その能力は
騎士とするに ふさわしいものです
それはお姉様も…
Viceroy!!
総督だ
あ…
Viceroy, even you must see that.
総督もその目でご覧になったはずです
ナンバーズを区別するのは
ブリタニアの国是だ
Discrimination against Numbers
is Britannian national policy!
では わたくしが変えてみせます
Then it's time I tried to change that!
ん…
分かっているのか？　副総督
Do you understand, Sub-Viceroy?
それは皇帝になる という事だぞ
For that, you must become empress!
思考エレベーターの構築は予定通りだな？
Construction of the thought elevator
is proceeding as scheduled.
ああ 分かっておる
Yes, I understand.
シュナイゼルが？
Schneizel?
Yes, Majesty. What's to be done about it?
はい　いかが致しましょう？
好きにさせよう
自信があるなら挑んでくればよい
Let him do as he pleases. If he believes
in himself, let him challenge me.
And now, to celebrate the
knighting of Suzaku Kururugi,
それでは 我がアッシュフォード学園
生徒会風紀委員
member of the Ashford Academy
student council dress-code committee!
枢木スザク君の騎士叙勲を祝いまして
Let the congratulations party commence!
おめでとうパーティー 開始！
かんぱーい！
Cheers!
Man, it's really incredible!
いやあ すっげえよなあ
おめでとう！　スザク君！
Congratulations, Suzaku!
企画 立案はナナリーだよ
The one who planned
and organized this was Nunnally.
お祝い いっぱいされたでしょうけど
I know you must be tired of celebrating by now,
but is it all right if we do it with you?
私達のも受けて頂けますか？
もちろん！　すっごく嬉しいよ
Of course!
I'm really touched by all this!
私 私はどうすれば…
ユーフェミア様…
What... What should I do, Princess Euphemia?
こんにちは
Hello there!
あ…
ねえ 君 枢木スザク少佐は？
ここにいるって…
Tell me, have you seen Maj. Kururugi?
They said he was here... Hm?
ん？
Ah! Looks like you're working
on some fun stuff here!
ん～ 面白そうな事やってるねえ
分かるんですか？
You understand it?
ウランでしょ？　質量数235の方
Uranium, right? The one with
an atomic mass of 235, I see.
あ はい！　そうなんです！
Yes, that's right! If you can get this
uranium 235 to absorb active neutrons,
このウラン235に
熱中性子を吸収させると
２つの原子核と
高速中性子に分裂するんです
it should cause it to split into two
atomic nuclei and high-speed neutrons!
でも問題は
燃料として使えるウラン235が
The problem is that the U-235
you'd use to fuel the reaction...
天然ウランの中には
0.7％しかない事なんです
only makes up 0.7 percent of
the uranium you find naturally.
いくら分裂させる為の装置を
用意してやっても
So even if we somehow built some
sort of device to induce fission,
we couldn't do the experiment
as things stand. That's why...
このままじゃ実験できないんですよね
だから…
会長 ニーナは？
Hey Prez, where's Nina?
んん 声は かけたんだけど…
I invited her, but...
ん…
あ カレン！　ピザ並べるの手伝って！
Oh, Kallen! Can you help me set out the pizzas?
ん…
おーい 聞こえてる？
Hey, are you listening to me?
ゼロの為よ カレン
This is for Zero, Kallen.
ここで殺らないと…
If I don't do it here...
あ！
は！
シャーリーが手伝って欲しいってさ
Shirley wants you to help her.
ごめんなさい
I'm sorry, but I have something
important to do right now.
今は大切な用事があって
なんだい？　その用事って？
What sort of thing?
あ！
あれ？
What's up?
んっ
悪い　遅くなった
Sorry. I got held up.
あっ
とんでもない！
No problem! I'm just glad you could come.
来てくれただけで嬉しいよ！
んっ
そうだ！　この間の事…
ほら 大切な話があるって
Oh yeah, what did you want to talk about?
You said it was important.
ああ…
Oh. About that... Forget it.
あれはその… もういいんだ
え？
残念でした！
Too bad!
ま～た仕事が増えちゃったね スザク君
You just got even more work to do, Suzaku.
あ… はあ
Uh, right...
誰？
Who's?
うちの上司
My boss.
ロイドさん　何か？
Lloyd, is something wrong?
あれ？　ミレイちゃん 知ってる人？
Oh? Milly, you know him?
婚約者だもん
I'm her fiancé.
え？
ええっ？
で いいんだよね？
I could say that, right?
あ… はあ…
Uh... Yes...
言っちゃった
He said it.
知ってたのか？
You knew?
うん
Yeah.
ちょおっと ちょっと
Whoa! Whoa! Who are?!
What's your name?!
あっじゃあ あんたが？
あ ん… 名前は？
ロイド伯爵
Earl Lloyd Asplund.
伯爵？
An EARL?! Uh, er...
Hello, your lordship.
あいや… ああ…
伯爵様？　その…
お２人は どういうご関係で？
So, anyway, what exactly is your relationship?
Her fiancé, I said.
だから婚約者
NO!!!
んなあー！
本気だったんだ
He was serious.
あのう…
Um... Is there some military business for me?
もしかして軍務ですか？
そ 大事なお客様が
船でいらっしゃるんでね
Yes, an important visitor is coming on his boat.
We're going to welcome him.
お出迎えを
もちろんランスロットと
ユーフェミア皇女殿下も一緒に
Along with Lancelot and
Princess Euphemia, of course.
うわあ！
ん…
CODE GEASS
Lelouch of the Rebellion
Why Shikine Island?
どうして式根島なんですか？
トウキョウ租界の方が安全なのに
The Tokyo Settlement would've been a lot safer.
私も教えて欲しいんですけど？
I'd like to know, too.
Wha?! You don't know, either, Cécile?
え？　セシルさんも知らないんですか？
Me, neither.
僕も
は？
それにしては うかつ過ぎません？
Even so, isn't this being a little too careless?
行動予定
ネットに上がっているみたいですよ
It looks like our movement
plans were leaked onto the Net.
面白い子がいたんで
ついサービスしちゃって
I did a little favor for a fascinating girl I met...
ユーフェミアが
本国からの貴族を出迎えに
Euphemia will be going to that island to meet
a nobleman arriving from the homeland.
あの島にやって来る
As her knight, Suzaku Kururugi
should be accompanying her.
騎士である枢木スザクも共にいるはずだ
戦略拠点ではない為
敵戦力も限られている
As this isn't a strategic point, the
enemy's strength will also be limited.
これはチャンスだ！
This is our chance!
The objective of this mission will be...
作戦の目的は
枢木スザク及びランスロットの捕獲
the capture of both Suzaku
Kururugi and the Lancelot.
戦場で勝って 堂々と捕虜にする
Win on the battlefield and we'll
capture him without any doubts.
うん
ふう
捕虜にして どうすんだ？
What happens after we capture him?
そこから先は私に任せてもらおう
Just leave everything after that to me.
この辺かねえ
This area, huh?
うまく いきそうですか？
You think it'll work?
大丈夫でしょ　副産物のステルスも
機能してるみたいだし
We're fine, aren't we? The stealth effect we
get as a byproduct seems to be working.
How can you tell?
どうして分かるんです？
Because the Britannians
haven't found us, have they?
だってブリタニアに
見つかってないじゃない　私達が
ああ それじゃあ！
Oh, you're right!
ファーストステップだけだけどね
It is just a first step, though.
ディートハルト
カレンに何を吹き込んだ？
Diethard, what did you convince Kallen to do?
I just asked her to do a private
investigation of Suzaku Kururugi.
枢木スザクの内偵を依頼しただけです
少々ふくみは持たせましたが
I may have implied that it be a bit more, though...
勝手な事をするな
私は暗殺を指示した覚えはない
Don't overstep yourself. I don't remember
ordering him to be assassinated.
結果的に卑劣な暗殺ではなく
Consequently, rather than cowardly assassins,
正義の鉄槌だと
民衆が思えばよいのでしょう？
you want the people to think of
us as the hammer of justice?
メディアを使えば真実は隠せる
You can use the media to hide the truth.
世界を掴むには
きれい事だけでは済まない
You can't take the world without
dirtying your hands. Am I wrong?
違いますか？
ディートハルト　お前の目的はなんだ？
Diethard... What are you really after?
左遷されたとはいえ
お前はブリタニア人だ
You may have been demoted,
but you're still a Britannian.
黒の騎士団に加わって
世界を変える必要などないだろう
You don't have to join the Black
Knights to change the world, do you?
私は あの枢木スザク強奪事件で
初めて あなたを見た
I first saw you when you snatched Suzaku Kururugi.
震えました
I trembled... It was as though a new
era had taken human form right there.
新しい時代が
人という形をとって そこにいる
私は あなたを撮りたい
I want to document you!
たった１人の男が組織を作り
国家を打倒し いずれ世界に君臨する
How a lone man built an organization,
defeated a nation, and
eventually controlled the world!
I want to be the man right there,
documenting history as it's being made!
その歴史を この私が
一番近くから記録する
こんなに心踊る事はない
Nothing has ever made my heart dance like this!
記録？
Documenting?
自ら事件に介入するのなら
それは ねつ造だな
When you insert yourself into the
events, you're fabricating it, aren't you?
主観なき情報などありえません
There's no such thing as objective information!
ゼロ　ジャーナリズムとは
所詮 人の意志が作るものです
Zero, in the end, journalism is
the product of a human mind.
お前の担当は軍事ではない
You're not in charge of military affairs.
承知しております
I understand.
到着時刻は予定通りです
Arrival time is right on schedule.
司令部に
控えの間を用意させておりますが
We've prepared a waiting area for you at
headquarters. What would you like to do?
いかが致しますか？
船は ここに寄港すると聞きましたが
Am I correct that the ship will be stopping here?
はい　変更はありません
Yes, that hasn't changed.
では待ちましょう
Then let's wait here.
分かりました
Very well, I'll just arrange for an escort for you... Hm?
警護担当は… ん？
Terrorists? But how did they get here?!
テロリストか？　どうやってここに？
一番隊 そのまま前進
Squad 1, continue advancing!
零番隊は一番隊の側面から援護しろ
Zero Squad, give support fire from Squad 1's flank!
イレヴンがあ！
Elevens!
あの子 意外とやるなあ
That gal packs a hell of a punch!
Impressive as always, Tohdoh.
さすがだな　藤堂
ナイトメアなしで ブリタニア軍に
土をつけただけの事はある
You defeated the Britannians without
any Knightmares once before.
あとはユーフェミアに
この情報が伝わればいい
All I need to do now is wait for
this news to reach Euphemia.
司令部が
何者かの攻撃を受けているようです
Headquarters appears to be
under attack by someone.
え？
We'd better withdraw to the settlement.
租界に引き返しましょう
護衛部隊の手配はできますか？
Can you arrange an escort for her?
かえって危険かもしれません
Going back there might be dangerous.
広範囲に浅くジャミングが
かけられているようでして
It looks like they've got a wide-range
superficial jamming field in operation.
ご安心ください
Don't worry. I'll protect
Princess Euphemia myself.
ユーフェミア様の事は自分が守ります
いえ あなたは
司令部の救援に向かって下さい
No, please go and help them
defend headquarters.
は？
副総督 彼は名誉ブリタニア人ですぞ
Sub-Viceroy, this man is an honorary Britannian!
敵は黒の騎士団である可能性が高い
The probability is high that the
enemy are the Black Knights.
ランスロットごと裏切ったら…
What if he turns the Lancelot against us?!
あの 分かってます？
Um, pardon. You do realize you're
criticizing a member of royalty, right?
それって皇族批判ですよ
あ いえ　そんなつもりは毛頭…
Oh, no! I didn't mean to!
枢木スザク
ここで あなたの力を示すのです
Suzaku Kururugi, demonstrate
your strength for us here.
If you do, those stupid rumors can finally stop.
そうすれば
いずれ雑音も消えるでしょう
はい
Right!
In the end, they're just a garrison unit!
所詮は守備部隊！
とどめ 頂き！
I'll finish him off!
ああ！
どあっ がっ！
くっ！
ゼロ… やっぱり
Zero! I thought as much!
さあ！　向かって来い スザク！
Come and get me, Suzaku!
対象を確認
Target confirmed.
各機 第３陣形を取りつつ後退せよ
All units, assume formation three and fall back.
対象には手を出すな
Do not fire on the target!
I say again, do not fire on the target!
繰り返す　対象には手を出すな！
は はい 特派のおかげで…
Yes, thanks to A.S.E.E.C.
ううっ しかしそれでは…
Wha? But, that would mean!
イエス ユア・ハイネス！
Yes, Your Highness!
砂地に装備なしで飛び込むなんて
He's jumping into a sandy area
without being equipped for it?
Or is he trying to surround the
Lancelot, using himself as bait?
それとも
ランスロットを囲むつもりか？
自らを おとりにして
しかし！
Even so!
ゼロ！　これで！
Zero! Now...
...you are...
お前を！
捕まえた
...trapped!
なんだ？
What the?!
く…
動けない？
I can't move!
駄目か
No good!
話がある　枢木スザク
I want to speak to you, Suzaku Kururugi!
出てきてくれないか？
Will you please come out?
Everything aside from your primary
power systems should still work.
第１駆動系以外は動かせるはずだ
捕虜の扱いについては国際法にのっとる
You'll be treated according to
international law as a prisoner.
話し合いにのらない場合 君は四方から
銃撃を受ける事になるが？
If you don't want to talk, would you prefer
to be gunned down from four directions?
くっ…
構いません！
スザクに出るよう伝えてください
I don't care! Please tell Suzaku to exit the unit!
Besides that, why isn't the Lancelot working?!
それより どうして
ランスロットは動かないんですか？
ナイトメアの駆動系に使われている
サクラダイト
The Sakuradite used to power the Knightmare...
そこに なんらかの干渉が…
Something's interfering with it!
ゲフィオンディスターバー
A Gefjun Disturber.
まさか！
You mean!
でも部分的にジャミングも働いてるし
But it's also partially being used as a jammer.
理論だけだと思っていたけど
うかつだったな
I thought it was just theoretical.
That was careless of me...
やはり君なのか？
It really is you, isn't it? Rakshata...
ラクシャータ
We still need to improve the
effective range and the duration.
効果範囲も持続時間もまだまだかぁ
枢木スザク　単刀直入に言おう
私の仲間になって欲しい
Suzaku Kururugi, I'll get straight to the point.
I want you to join me.
それは脅しかい？
Is that a threat? Even so, I refuse!
だとしても断る
前にも言ったはずだ！
I told you before, any results gained through
the wrong methods are meaningless!
間違った方法で手に入れた結果に
意味はないって
では 聞こう
Then answer me this! Isn't the peace
we have now meaningless as well?
今の平和にも意味はないのか？
う…
７年前 日本が徹底抗戦を選んでいたら
どうなっていたと思う？
What do you think would have happened...
if Japan had chosen the course of
do-or-die resistance 7 years ago?
中華連邦とＥＵが介入し
The Chinese Federation and
the E.U. would have intervened,
and Japan would have been
split into three parts.
日本は３つに分断され
未だに戦い続けていただろう
They'd probably still be fighting even now!
つまり 今の平和は いち早く決まった
無条件降伏によるものだ
In short, the current peace is the result
of an immediate unconditional surrender.
あ…
That's right.
そうだ
父さんの築いた平和を壊さない為に
自分は戦っている
Yes, that's right, and I've been fighting to
preserve the peace that my father built!
違うな　間違っているぞ
No, you're wrong.
降伏は選挙で選ばれた枢木首相ではなく
彼を殺した何者かが勝手に決めた事だ
Surrender wasn't the choice of Prime Minister
Kururugi, who had been elected to his post,
but rather the selfish decision of
whoever it was who killed him!
あ！
政府の指揮系統に乱れが起こり
降伏を選ぶしか なくなった
With the government's command
line thrown into confusion,
surrender became the only choice to make.
分かるな？
Do you understand? The will of
the people was stolen from them.
人々の意思は奪われたのだ
ルールを破った１人の犯罪者によって
By a lone criminal who broke the
rules for his own selfish reasons!
勝手に！
聞き取れますか？
Can you hear what they're saying?
マイクのノイズが大きすぎて…
There's too much static on the mic!
あ… どうして それを…
How do you know that?
１つだけ しょく罪する方法がある
There's only one way to atone for that.
え？
あの時の日本人が選べなかった選択肢を
身を持って提示する事だ
Present the Japanese people with the
choice they weren't able to make then.
７年前に盗まれた
ブリタニアと戦うという道を
The path of fighting Britannia which
was robbed from them 7 years ago.
戦う… またそれか！
Fighting?! That again?!
これも１つの道だ
It's a choice to consider.
君は自分のエゴを 多くの人々に
未来永劫に渡って押しつけるつもりか？
Do you intend to forever drive the masses
towards a future dictated by your own egotism?!
それが平和だというのか？
You call that peace?!
ん…
Do you read me, Maj. Kururugi? Respond!
応答しろ
聞こえるか？　枢木少佐
いいかな？
May I?
好きにしたまえ
As you wish.
こちらはブリタニア軍
式根島基地司令 パイエル中佐だ
This is Lt. Colonel Fayer, commander of
the Britannian base here on Shikine Island!
これよりテロリストに対し
地対地ミサイルを撃ち込む
We're launching surface to surface
missiles against the terrorists!
Maj. Kururugi, you are ordered to keep Zero there!
枢木少佐は
その場にゼロを足止めせよ！
なっ！　部下に死を命じるのか！
He's ordering his subordinate to die?!
ぬっ… くっ！
Kururugi, what are you?!
枢木！　お前は…
君のやり方には賛同できない
I can't approve of your methods!
All I can do right now is this!
今 自分にできる事は！
あいつ！
Why, that!
動くな　力場の干渉を受けるぞ
Don't move!
You'll be affected by the field, too!
But!
でも…
ポートマンを警護につかせます
We've assigned a Portman to escort you.
For now, the sub-viceroy should escape from...
副総督はひとまず この…
お待ちなさい！
Wait!
ランスロットを壊すつもり？
You're going to wreck the Lancelot?!
枢木少佐が足止めをしています
Kururugi is holding him there.
今ならゼロを倒せるのです
This is our chance to kill Zero!
誰がそんな作戦を！
枢木スザクは わたくしの騎士ですよ？
Who came up with that plan?!
Suzaku Kururugi is my personal knight!
これは準１級命令です
It was a para-level one command.
命令の撤回は総督以上か
It can be countermanded by
only the viceroy herself...
３名以上の将官クラスの
合意によってのみ行われます
or by the agreement of
at least three generals!
Then who issued the order?!
Get me a line to them at once!
だから
そんな指示を下したのは誰です？
私にラインを繋ぎなさい
準１級命令です　ユーフェミア副総督
It was a para-level one command,
Sub-Viceroy Euphemia.
ん…
うわ！
おどきなさい！
Out of my way!
うわっ
副総督！
Sub-Viceroy!
基地に伝えなさい！
わたくしが巻き込まれる危険があると
Tell the base that there's the
danger I'll be caught in the attack!
それでも発射命令を出せますか？
Or are they still going to launch?!
わがままも たいがいにして頂きたい！
Don't be so self-centered!
あの… ユーフェミア様なら…
Do you think they'll stop this for Princess Euphemia?
ダメじゃないかな？　それでも…
No, not even for her, I think.
接近するミサイルを確認！
Incoming missiles, confirmed!
ええい！
Zero, I'll save you!
ゼロ！　今助けに！
しまった！
Dammit!
くっ！
You're going to die as well!
Do you really not mind that?!
このままでは お前も死ぬ！
本当にそれでいいのか？
う…
Maj. Kururugi, you won't be dying in vain!
枢木少佐 これは無駄死にではないぞ
あ…
国家反逆の大罪人ゼロを
確実に葬る事ができるのだ
We'll be able to bury Zero, the traitor
to our homeland, once and for all!
They'll be talking about your
bravery for generations to come!
貴公の武勲は
後々まで語り継がれる事になろう
Shut up!
黙れ！
All Knightmares, set up a barrage
against those incoming missiles!
全ナイトメア！
飛来するミサイルに対して弾幕を張れ！
全弾 撃ち尽くしても構わん！
Empty your guns if you have to!
スザク！　ゼロを放せ！
Suzaku, let Zero go!
私は…
It's me! It's me! Kallen Stadtfeld
from the student council!
私は生徒会の
カレン・シュタットフェルトだ！
Look at me!
こっちを見ろ！
スザク まだ死んではなりません
Suzaku, you can't die now!
軍人は
命令に従わなければ ならないんだ！
A soldier has to follow his orders!
ふん！　その方が楽だからな
人に従ってる方が！
Certainly easier than following your own heart!
あ！
お前 自身はどうなんだ！
How do you feel about this?!
違う！　これは俺が決めた俺のルール
You're wrong! I'm doing this by my own rules!
あ…
あ！
ああ！
フロートシステムかぁ　やられた
A float system?! Well, that beats me.
あ！
あれは…
That's big brother's Avalon!
お兄様のアヴァロン…
な… なんだ？
Wh-What the?!
スザク！　このままでは本当に死ぬぞ！
Suzaku! If you don't do something,
you're really going to die!
Better that than breaking more rules!
ルールを破るよりいい！
この分からず屋が！
You stubborn fool!
あ！
モザイクカケラ ひとつひとつ
Mosaic kakera
The pieces of a mosaic
Hitotsu hitotsu tsunagiawasete
Coming together one by one
繋ぎ合わせて描いてゆく
Egaiteyuku
To form the picture
あなたがくれた 出逢いと別れも
Anata ga kureta deai to wakare mo
The meetings and partings I've had with you
Konna hazu ja nai
"It can't be," I think
こんなはずじゃない そう思って眠り
Sou omotte nemuri
As I go to sleep
Mezamereba itsumo no
When I awaken, just as always
目覚めればいつもの 変わらない空回り
Kawaranai karamawari
I'm left going nowhere
Imi mo naku kurikaeshi
Pointlessly repeating the pattern
意味もなく繰り返し
Mosaic kakera
The pieces of a mosaic
モザイクカケラ 鮮やかに映す
Azayaka ni utsusu
Clearly showing
過去の嘘も過ちも
Kako no uso mo ayamachi mo
The lies and mistakes of the past
消してしまいたいと想えば想うほど
Keshiteshimaitai to omoeba omou hodo
As much as I'd like to erase them
Furikaereba soko ni aru
When I look back, I see...
振り返れば
そこにあるスタートライン
Start line mada susun ja inai
I still haven't moved past that start line
未だ進んじゃいない
Mou ichido yume wo
So let's try regathering
もう一度夢を拾い集めてみよう
Hiroiatsumete miyou
the pieces of our dream
Mosaic kakera
The pieces of a mosaic
モザイクカケラ ひとつひとつ
Hitotsu hitotsu tsunagiawasete
Coming together one by one
繋ぎ合わせて描いてゆく
Egaiteyuku
To form the picture
Anata ga kureta deai to wakare mo
The meetings and partings I've had with you
あなたがくれた 出逢いと別れも
俺のギアスは命じる力
My Geass is the power to command others.
誰も俺に逆らう事はできない
No one can defy me.
そして命じられた対象者は
And those I use it on...
自分の倫理を 考えを思いを
踏みにじられる
end up having their ethics, their thoughts,
and their feelings crushed beneath its power.
そんな事は全て分かった上で
And I, knowing all of that...
俺はスザクに…
ISLAND OF THE GODS
I use it on Suzaku.